you might be surprised by how easy it is
to make crepes at home
here's a basic recipe you can try for
yourself start by sifting pastry flour
into a large bowl
sifting the flour helps to get rid of
lumps in the batter so your crepes come
out beautifully smooth
next add one tablespoon of sugar and a
quarter teaspoon of salt to the flour
and whisk to combine now it's time to
add the wet ingredients
starting with milk we used whole milk
but pretty much any kind of milk will
work
followed by two whole eggs give the
batter a really good whisk
this isn't like pancake batter where you
want to leave lumps for the ideal
crepe batter you need it super super
smooth so to ensure there are absolutely
no lumps strain the batter through a
sieve and use a spatula to push it
through
now you're ready to start cooking melt
some butter in a non-stick or cast iron
pan over medium heat
use a ladle to scoop a portion of the
batter into the pan then gently swirl
the pan so the batter spreads out evenly
across the surface
cook for about one minute then use a
spatula to gently flip the crepe
and cook for about another minute on the
other side this recipe will make roughly
8 to 10 crepes of this size
you're now ready to add any filling you
like we stuck with the classic nutella
but fruit or jam would be amazing as
well
fold the crepe into quarters and you're
ready to serve
subscribe to dish for more basic recipes